{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. In an EMSA experiment sample runs from",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Cathode to anode",
        "b": "Anode to cathode",
        "c": "Both a and b",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. In EMSA the percentage of the gel depends on ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Charge of the protein",
        "b": "Molecular weight of the target DNA",
        "c": "Size and number of the protein",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Bromophenol blue is used in EMSA ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "As a tracking dye",
        "b": "To label protein",
        "c": "To label DNA",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. In EMSA DNA probe can be",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Radiolabeled",
        "b": "Fluorescent labeled",
        "c": "Both a and b ",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. In EMSA low ionic strength buffer is used",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To stabilize transient interactions",
        "b": "To break transient interactions",
        "c": "To inhibit hydrophobic interactions between protein-nucleic acid",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Factors that affect the strength and specificity of the proteinâ€“DNA interactions under study include",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The ionic strength and pH of the binding buffer",
        "b": "Presence of glycerol or carrier proteins (e.g., BSA)",
        "c": "The presence/absence of divalent cations (e.g., Mg<sup>2+</sup> or Zn<sup>2+</sup>)",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Before a binding reaction is performed, gels are pre-run at a constant voltage (30-90 minutes) in a cold room or using other methods to keep the gel cool ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "to remove all traces of ammonium persulfate  ",
        "b": "to ensure a constant gel temperature",
        "c": "to equilibrate any special stabilizing factors or ions that were added to the electrophoresis buffer",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Method alternative to Electrophoretic Mobility Shift Assay (EMSA) for studying protein-DNA interactions",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Chromatin Immunoprecipitation (ChIP)",
        "b": "DNA Footprinting",
        "c": "Surface Plasmon Resonance (SPR)",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Why sometimes there are multiple bands in EMSA",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Because of the dissociation occurs during electrophoresis ",
        "b": "A single DNA molecule has multiple binding sites for an individual protein",
        "c": "Both a and b ",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. EMSA is important for ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Studying the affinity of protein-DNA interactions ",
        "b": "Studying the specificity of protein-DNA interactions",
        "c": "Identifying DNA-binding proteins",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
